Dominic Schmidt-Toms

References available upon request

Profile

Full stack developer with a keen interest in all things computers. Experienced in many high level programming languages, web development, cloud computing and games development. Recently graduated from the University of East Anglia with a bachelors in computing science. When I'm not programming, I enjoy performing DJ mixes at local clubs, longboarding around the countryside and cooking vegetarian food.

Employment

Self Employed Computer Science Tutor

Python · JavaScript · Haskell · React · MySQL

From Jun 2023 until present

- · Helped many GCSE and A-Level students reach A* proficiency in computer science.
- · Assisted multiple first and second-year university students in achieving first-class grades.
- Provided daily tutoring to many students with diverse skill levels and backgrounds in coding.

Magicave Game Developer

Unity · Kubernetes · Docker · GCP · MongoDB

From Feb 2022 until Jun 2023

- Successfully wrote multiple no-code tools allowing designers to build levels and modify game statistics.
- Developed and deployed backend infrastructure for the game using Kubernetes through Google Cloud Platform.
- · Co-wrote the character creation system for the company's flagship game.

Phlashweb Software Developer

C# • .NET • ASP.NET • Azure • SQL Server

From Aug 2021 until Feb 2022

- Resolved multiple security vulnerabilities in the client's customer-facing website.
- Restructured, migrated and redeployed the clients SQL database, improving backend performance.
- · Maintained and improved internal tools for the client's warehouse workers.

Fruitlab Game Development Internship

TypeScript • React Native • WebGL • AWS • RDS

From Feb 2021 until Aug 2021

- Developed and completed a web-based game using WebGL for playback on web and mobile devices.
- Wrote and deployed leaderboard services using TypeScript, Amazon Web Services and Amazon RDS.
- Collaborated with designers to ensure the game always met visual and gameplay requirements.

Education

University of East Anglia BSc in Computing Science

Java • Node.js • C++ • Unix • Postgres

From Sep 2020 until Jun 2024

- Served as vice president of the Computer Science Society, organised multiple events for the society.
- Handled promotional material and social media for the Electronic Music Society, improved event turnout rates.
- · Wrote my dissertation on cellular automata and John Conway's Game of Life, exploring computational theory.